<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>Quick Paint Terrain Brush Dev Tool</name>
    <author>ProgrammerLily</author>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modVersion>2.0.0</modVersion>
    <packageId>BrushTool.programmerLily.com</packageId>
    <modDependencies>
    </modDependencies>
    <description>Comprehensive terrain painting toolkit for RimWorld map designers and developers. Includes both solid brushes and spray paint tools for creating natural, varied terrain patterns.

This mod provides advanced terrain painting tools with circular brushes and spray functionality. Perfect for rapid terrain prototyping, map design, and creating realistic terrain transitions.

Features:
• Circular Brushes: Single cell, radius 1, 2, 4, 8, 16, and 32
• Spray Paint Tools: 5%, 10%, and 20% coverage for varied terrain patterns
• Edge Blender Tools: Smart terrain transition blending with light, medium, and heavy strength options
• Paint-while-dragging: Hold and drag to paint continuously
• Visual brush preview under mouse cursor
• All terrain types supported through intuitive submenus
• Integrated into Debug Menu under "Terrain Painter" category

Tools Available:
• Brushes: Full coverage circular painting tools for solid terrain areas
• Light Spray Paint (5%): Ultra-sparse coverage for subtle terrain hints and transitions
• Spray Paint (10%): Medium sparse coverage for natural terrain mixing
• Heavy Spray Paint (20%): Dense coverage for strong terrain variation and blending
• Edge Blender Tools: Intelligent terrain boundary smoothing with configurable blend strength

Usage:
1. Open the Debug Menu (Development mode required)
2. Search for "Terrain Painter" in the Actions/tools
3. Choose tool type: 
   - "Brushes" for solid coverage
   - "Light Spray Paint (5%)" for ultra-sparse coverage
   - "Spray Paint (10%)" for medium sparse coverage
   - "Heavy Spray Paint (20%)" for dense coverage
   - "Edge Blender Tools" for intelligent terrain boundary smoothing
4. Select desired radius and/or blend strength
5. Choose terrain type from submenu (for brush/spray tools)
6. Click and drag on map to paint terrain

The spray paint tools apply terrain randomly to a percentage of cells within the brush radius: 5% for subtle hints, 10% for natural mixing, and 20% for strong variation. The Edge Blender tools automatically detect terrain boundaries and create smooth transitions by intelligently blending different terrain types based on surrounding context.</description>
</ModMetaData>
